J. ELLIOT MILLER

741 Chapel Road \diamond Gettysburg, Pennsylvania 17325-8706 717-398-1540 \diamond jem
060@bucknell.edu

BIO

Elliot is a recent computer science graduate of Bucknell University. Through his own startup, he has been involved with the launch and operations of several small businesses. Now that he's preparing to synthesize his technology and business foundations, he laments the lack of time to explore the rich world of late '80s video games.

ELEVATOR PITCH

Elliot combines a broad array of skills and experiences from across disciplines, collar colors, and industries to be a leader who can understand and communicate with people from any position or background, and a worker who can fill almost any role and occupy any space.

June 2016 - May 2019

June 2014 - May 2017

Overall GPA: 3.96/4

Overall GPA: 3.55/4

EDUCATION

Bucknell University

Bachelor of Arts

Department of Computer Science

College of Arts and Sciences

Minor in Philosophy

Statistical Literacy for the 21st Century (A-); Psychology of Attraction and Relationships (A-); Caribbean Literature (A); Software Engineering and Design (A-); Intro Latin (B); Calculus III (C+); Computer Organization and Programming (B+); Life, Computers, and Everything (A); Discrete Structures (B+); Logic (A); Computer Science Design Project (B+); Operating System Design (B+); Algorithms (B+); Philosophy of Peace and Nonviolence (A); Cognitive Science (AU); Human-Computer Interaction (A-); Symbolic Logic (A); Philosophy of Society and Politics (B+); Consciousness, Self and Mind (A); Wireless System Design (AU).

Harrisburg Area Community College

Associate of Arts

Department of Mathematics and Computer Science

Modern Culture and the Arts (A); Intro to Statistics (A); English Composition (A); Trigonometry (A); Principles of Accounting I (A); Pre-Calculus (A); General Psychology (A); Principles of Accounting II (A); Effective Speaking (A); Applied Calculus for Business (A); Principles of Marketing (A); General Biology I (A); Java Programming (A); Calculus I (A); Introduction to Sociology (A); Intro to Computer Systems (A); Computer Science I (A); Object Oriented Programming (B); Calculus II (A); Beginning Self-Defence (A); General Inorganic Chemistry I (A); Computer Science II (A); Discrete Mathematics (A); Linear Algebra (A).

NCCER May 2013 - April 2014

HVAC/R and Construction Training

Reference #: 11142092

Core Curricula; Basic Safety; Intro to Construction Math; Intro to Hand Tools; Intro to Power Tools; Intro to Construction Drawings; Basic Communication Skills; Basic Employability Skills; Intro to Material Handling; Intro to HVAC; Trade Mathematics; Copper and Plastic Piping Practices; Soldering and Brazing; Ferrous Metal Piping Practices; Basic Electricity; Intro to Cooling; Intro to Heating; Air Distribution Systems; Commercial Airside Systems; Chimneys, Vents, and Flues; Into to Hydronic

Systems; Air Quality Equipment; Leak Detection, Evacuation, Recovery, and Charging; Alternating Current; Basic Electronics; Intro to Control Circuit Troubleshooting; Troubleshooting Gas Heating; Troubleshooting Cooling; Heat Pumps; Basic Installation and Maintenance Practices; Sheet Metal duct Systems; Fiberglass and Flexible Duct Systems; Intro to Photovoltaics; Site Assessment; System Design; System Installation and Inspection; Maintenance and Troubleshooting; Your Role in the Green Environment; 10 Hour Construction Site Safety Orientation; HVAC Level One; Solar Photovoltaics System Installer; Solar Photovoltaic; HVAC Level Two.

Ferris State University

August 2013

Geothermal for Home Certification

Ohio University

June 2011 - August 2011

Course Work

Overall GPA: 4/4

College Algebra (A); Writing and Reading: Gender (A).

PA Highlands Community College

January 2009 - December 2009

Certificate of Office Technology

Overall GPA: 4/4

Microsoft Excel (A); Microsoft Word (A); Microsoft ACCESS (A); Microsoft PowerPoint (A); Theory of Computing (A).

Pennsylvania Department of Education

Various

-Needs work. Are those two really the same department? Also, add grades to ged and detail to drafting.-

GED; Drafting stuff

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Bucknell University

June 2018 - Present

Undergraduate Research

- · Employed SciKitLearn to construct machine learning classifier used in analyzing effectiveness of epsilon-Differential Privacy data protections.
- · Built custom application to extract and present experiment results across seven variables
- · Presented research at Susquehanna Valley Summer Research Symposium

The Bayeux Group

November 2014 - September 2017

Owner/Manager

· I founded this company to provide business services to hopeful entrepreneurs. Under my management, we directly handled the launch of two companies, and we have been involved with the management of several others. I have personally been handled bookkeeping, administration, supply chain management, marketing, customer management, sales, strategic planning, and data analytics on behalf of our clients. The company was suspended in order for myself to return to school to further develop my critical problem solving skills and technological knowledge.

Marissa Deihl, SP

September 2018 - Present

Software Developer

- · Works on software development team of one programmer (me) and one electrical engineer.
- · Primarily responsible for designing and implementing project goals in code.
- · Manages user testing and feedback in iterative design process.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages Software & Tools $\mathrm{C}/\mathrm{C}++,$ Java, Python, Visual Basic, $\mathrm{C}\#$

Unity, LaTeX, Git, Gimp, Microsoft Office Suit, AutoCAD

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Bucknell Community College Scholars Program Scholarship

Ranked second in Strategic Analysis and Decision making at Phi Beta Lambda state conference 2015

RELEVANT COURSES

Core Courses

Discrete Structures

Calculus III

Algorithms

Life, Computers & Everything

Software Engineering and Design

Other Courses

Computer Organization & Programming

Operating Systems

Logic

Linear Algebra

Cognitive Science (Audit)

INTERESTS

Student Government

Ballroom Dance

Student Driver

Martial Arts

Gran Fondo Cyclist